Jeff Ashear

ASNEar Full Stack Spokane, Washington

303.898.3638

kinesthesiac@gmail.com

Full Stack Developer

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-ashear

GitHub: https://github.com/Jeff-Ashear Portfolio: https://jeff-ashear.github.io/

Career Summary

Full Stack Developer with certification and a master's in composition, pursuing a full-time position in full stack or front end web development. Experience with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap JS, Jquery, Node, Express, Handlebars, MySQL, MongoDB, and React. Award-winning composer with relevant experience creating object programming-based virtual instruments, sound-sculpture and installations.

Technical Skills

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.JS, Express, APIs, Handlebars, MySQL, Firebase, MongoDB, React, Postman, GIT, GitHub, Heroku, REST, JSON.

Logic, MaxMSP, PureData, SPEAR, Ableton Live, Max for Live, cueMix, Audacity.

Superior knowledge of music. Proficient researcher.

_

Applications Built

Sproso:

Deployed: https://tinyurl.com/sproso-repo
Repo: https://tinyurl.com/sproso-repo

-Full stack MERN app with a robust database structure. Provides game-ified social goal tracking for staying connected during stay at home.

-Creator and lead developer and UI/UX designer. Uses MySQL, React.js, React Bootstrap, custom CSS animations, Axios, and the DoppelMe API.

Google Books Search:

Deployed: https://tinyurl.com/book-searcher Repo: https://tinyurl.com/book-searcher

- -Light weight MERN stack app allowing the user to search Google Books using its api to see relevant info, view and purchase externally, and save it to a database.
- -Solo project. MongoDB, Mongoose, MLab, Axios, React.js, React Bootstrap

gamer.Ready:

Deployed: https://tinyurl.com/gamer-ready
Repo: https://tinyurl.com/gamer-ready-repo

- -A fan hub and market research tool, makes persistent commonly searched-for data about released and upcoming games.
- -Creator and lead developer. -Full stack work. Uses Javascript, Bootstrap, JQ, ajax, JSON,

Experience

TeamLIMS/ Application Developer

2020 - Present, Spokane, WA

Test the workflow of an enterprise laboratory information management system application and discover new feature needs. Develop those new features using Javascript, ES5, CSS, Angular.js, MongoDB, and VirtualBox. Develop test scripts for new and existing features using Protractor.

Creative Blue Media / Full Stack Web Developer

2020-Present, Spokane, WA

Internship. Helped the team realize a client-developer dashboard app by using adapting D3JS to work in a React.js. Environment to create a powerful data visualization tool/UI, allowing the user to see project progress at a glance as it guides them towards the best communication option for inquiries.

Self-Employed / Composer

2009 - Present, Denver, CO

Composed and performed award-winning works of music. My music has been performed in concert halls across the U.S. and Europe in concert halls at recitals, conventions, and competitions. My music pushes the boundaries of the art utilizing the latest technologies to invent entirely new performance practices and immersive, challenging listening experiences.

Education

University of Denver / Coding Bootcamp

Certificate course covering full stack web development and methods for continued study.

University of Denver / Masters of Music, Composition

Developed my own path of independent study to incorporate digital tools into modern concert music creation. Softwares include Logic, MaxMSP, PureData, SPEAR, Ableton Live, Max for Live, cueMix, Audacity.

Montana State University, Bozeman / Bachelor of Arts

Specialization in classical guitar performance, recording engineering and composition.

Awards

Multiple competition awards for new works of music

DU Outstanding Composer, Lamont School of Music

DU Playground Commission Award, Lamont School of Music

MSU Community Service Award

MSU Award for Excellence